JORDAN LAYNE

Software Developer

SUMMARY

Passionate Software Engineer with over 3 years of experience in developing web applications and backend systems. Skilled at writing clear, concise code that is easy to maintain and troubleshoot. Collaborated with both small and large teams on multiple projects. Able to work independently in remote or office environments. Eager to contribute expertise to new opportunities in software development.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Developer

2020 - Present

System One

Remote

- Implemented effective and efficient automated tests in collaboration with product developers, ensuring high-quality software delivery.
- Designed and developed reusable software components which used in 3 different project with reducing development effort by 50%
- Collaborated with an Agile Scrum team to design, develop, and support the production of software, driving successful outcomes.
- Conducted comprehensive code reviews, ensuring code quality, adherence to best practices, and identifying areas for improvement.

Travel Nurse Recruiter

2020 - 2020

White Glove Placements Inc

Remote

- Fostered strong relationships with clients, nurses, and internal teams, cultivating a network of trust and collaboration.
- Effectively managed multiple recruiting projects, consistently meeting deadlines and aligning with company policies.
- Utilized a strategic sourcing approach to identify and screen top-tier travel nurses, ensuring high-quality placements in healthcare facilities.

Route Manager

2019 - 2020

Affinity Waste Solutions

Greenville.SC

- Collaborated closely with property managers, ensuring prompt and efficient waste management services, resulting in high client satisfaction.
- Supervised and trained a team of valet service providers, fostering a culture of excellence and teamwork.
- Utilized data-driven insights to optimize trash valet routes, increasing operational
 efficiency and reducing costs.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Engineering, Software Engineering

2021 - Present

Western Governors University

Greenville,SC

Full Stack Software Engineering certification

2022 - 2023

Practicum



ACHIEVEMENTS

Played a Key role in the development and implementation of effective automated tests

resulting in improved product quality and increased efficiency in collaboration with product developers.

Achieved 30% improvement in query efficiency

by redesigning and optimizing the two largest MySQL databases, resulting in faster data retrieval and processing times. Enhanced system performance and user experience.

SKILLS

Tools

HTML · CSS · Javascript · Node.js ·

Google Cloud · Oracle · Firebase ·

Mongodb · C# · React · OOP · Angular ·

TypeScript · mySQL · ASP.NET

Operating Systems

Unix · Solaris · Linux · Windows

STRENGTHS

Collaboration

Proven ability to collaborate effectively with cross-functional teams, fostering strong relationships with clients, colleagues, and stakeholders to drive successful outcomes.

Analytical Thinking

Analytical mindset and the ability to identify areas for improvement, optimize processes, and make datadriven decisions to enhance efficiency and effectiveness.